How do you find an enemy who is hidden right before your eyes?
Tinker Tailor Soldier Spy is a drama, thriller,
mystery film directed by Tomas Alfredson.
In the bleak days of the Cold War, espionage veteran George Smiley is forced from
semi-retirement to uncover a Soviet mole within his former colleagues at the heart of MI6.
George Smiley, played by Gary Oldman.
Bill Haydon, played by Colin Firth.
Ricki Tarr, played by Tom Hardy.
Control, played by John Hurt.
Percy Alleline, played by Toby Jones.
Jim Prideaux, played by Mark Strong.
Tinker Tailor Soldier Spy is a 1974 spy novel by the author and
former secret intelligence officer John le Carré.
It follows the endeavours of the taciturn, ageing spymaster George Smiley to
uncover a Soviet mole in the British Secret Intelligence Service.
The novel has received critical acclaim for its complex social commentary—and,
at the time, relevance, following the defection of Kim Philby.
It was followed by The Honourable Schoolboy in 1977 and Smiley's People in 1979.
The three novels together make up the "Karla Trilogy", named after Smiley's long-time nemesis Karla,
the head of Soviet foreign intelligence and the trilogy's overarching antagonist.
The novel has been adapted into both a television series and a
film, and remains a staple of the spy fiction genre.
In 2022, the novel was included on the "Big Jubilee Read" list of 70 books by
Commonwealth authors, selected to celebrate the Platinum Jubilee of Elizabeth II.
The film explores themes of london, england,
budapest, hungary, espionage, spy, cold war.
The tone is intense and mind_bending and dark.